(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-02T17:04:12.000624",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
皆さん聞こえておりますでしょうかー？
Can everyone hear meー?
はーい！
Hii!
えーなんだっけ？えー、こ、うんと、えー、こうか？ホロライズ…3期生、えー、宝鐘海賊団船長の！
Umm, what was it? Um, c-, um, um, is this it? Hololive... 3rd Gen, um, Captain of the Houshou Pirates!
宝鐘マリンでーす！皆さん、聞こえてますか？
It's Houshou Marine! Everyone, can you hear me?
イェーイ、も、もう可愛い、いやだ、照れてしまう。
Yay! S-, so cute, no, I'm getting shy.
皆さん、今日は何の日かご存知ですか？えっ、いやだそんなに思い出しちゃダメ。
Everyone, do you know what today is? Eh, no, don't make me remember like that.
やっていいんだけど照れちゃう。うん。
It's fine to do it, but I get embarrassed. Yeah.
あのですね、今日はですね、なんと宝鐘マリン1周年なんです！
Well, you see, today is, believe it or not, Houshou Marine's 1st anniversary!
やあ、なんかややこしい。なんかややこしい。いやあの、1周年って言うと、あの
Man, it's kind of confusing. Kind of confusing. Well, you know, when I say 1st anniversary, um,
船長が1周年ってことは、3期生もね、これで全員1周年になりました。
Captain's 1st anniversary means all 3rd Gen members have now reached their 1st anniversary too.
いや本当にね、なんか長いようで短かったような、不思議な気分ですね。
Man, honestly, it feels kind of long yet short, a mysterious feeling.
ちょっと息が切れてるんですけど、あのこれは色々あって、既に息切れなんですけど。
I'm running out of breath a bit, um, this is because of various things, I'm already out of breath.
いやですね、今日も船レンタルしたの。あ、あれ、あの他人の船。あのですね
Well, you see, I rented a boat today too. Ah, that, um, someone else's boat. Um, you see
そう、船長がね、ここまでやってこられたのはね、まあもちろんホロライブ、ホロライブという存在、そして先輩たち、そしてね、もちろん同期のみんなに
Yeah, the reason Captain made it this far is, of course, Hololive, the existence of Hololive, and our seniors, and of course, all my generation mates,
そして後輩たちね？明後日からもさらに、さらに後輩がやってきて、ホロライブはどんどん大きな箱になっていく。ね、そんな中、船長のね
and our juniors, right? Starting the day after tomorrow, even more juniors are coming, and Hololive is becoming an ever bigger box. Right, amidst all that, Captain's
思い出とか今振り返りたいなって思ったけど。
memories and stuff, I thought I wanted to look back on them now.
はあ、思い出といえば思い出すな。皆さん覚えてます？船長の3D
Haa, speaking of memories, I remember. Everyone remember? Captain's 3D
記念お披露目配信のときにやった、ハレハレユカイのこと。覚えてる？みんな。はあ、あれは悲しかった。
debut stream, doing Hare Hare Yukai. Remember? Everyone. Haa, that was sad.
孤独だったな。1人でハレハレユカイ踊るって。さあ、悲しいよ、だって。ねえ、5人か3人は普通さ、集まるじゃん。
It was lonely. Dancing Hare Hare Yukai all by myself. Come on, it's sad, because. Right, 5 or 3 people normally, like, gather.
はあ、3人でハレハレユカイを踊りたい。はあ。はあ。
Haa, I want to dance Hare Hare Yukai with 3 people. Haa. Haa.
3人でハレハレユカイが踊りたいな。はあ。
I want to dance Hare Hare Yukai with 3 people. Haa.
お待たせしました！
Sorry to keep you waiting!
え！？もしかして…あー！白銀とみこる…じゃなくて、白銀と！
Eh!? Could it be... Ahー! Shirogane and Mikoru... no, Shirogane and!
行くわよ！みこる…じゃなくて、ゆき！来てくれたの！？きっつ！
Here we go! Mikoru... no, Yuki! You came?! Hardcore!
待って自己紹介やるんだった。ちょっと待って、あの順にちょっともう1回入り直して。
Wait, we were supposed to do self-introductions. Hold on, let's re-enter in order once more.
やり直された！順番に入ってこいよちょっと。あ、じゃあええと一番
We're redoing it! Come in in order. Ah, then um, the most
下手そうなじゃあノエルから。はい！えでもこれ、わかる。
awkward-looking one, Noel first. Yes! Eh, but this, I get it.
牛丼大好き、鉄の女、白銀ノエル！キュアノエル！きゅ、きゅっ…！
Huge fan of gyudon, iron woman, Shirogane Noel! Cure Noel! Pukyu...!
侵略は全部燃やす！え、キュアフレア！ださい…そう言うカニ似たような移動…
Burn all invasions! Um, Cure Flare! Lame... crab-like movement...
深海に沈む、1つぶの真珠。ほ、違う、キュアマリン！キュアマリンているよなー
Sinking in the deep sea, a single pearl. Ho, wait, Cure Marine! There is a Cure Marine, huhー
われら…われら…ちょっと待って、いぇいじゃない、われら！あ、われら始まった！われら！
We... We... Wait, not yay, we! Ah, we started! We!
ホロライブ、ホロ、ホロ…ホロファン！お姉さん組ー！
Hololive, Holo, Holo... Holo-fun! Older sisters groupー!
ナゾナゾみたいに地球儀を解き明かしたら
If we solve the globe like a riddle,
みんなでどこまでも行けるね
we can go anywhere together.
ワクワクしたいと願いながら過ごしてたよ
I spent my time wishing to be excited.
叶えてくれたのは誰なの？
Who granted my wish?
時間の果てまでBoooon!!
To the end of time, boooom!
ワープでループなこの想いは 何もかもを巻き込んだイメージで遊ぼう
This feeling of warping and looping, let's play with imagination that involves everything.
ナゾナゾみたいに地球儀を解き明かしたら
If we solve the globe like a riddle,
みんなでどこまででも行けるね
we can go anywhere together.
ワクワクしたいと願いながら過ごしてたよ
I spent my time wishing to be excited.
かなえてくれたのは誰なのだろう?
Who was it that granted my wish?
時間の果てまでBoooon!!
To the end of time, Boooon!!
ワープでループみなこの想いは何者をも巻き込んだ妄想で遊ぼう
With a warping, looping thought, let's play with an all-encompassing imagination.
アル晴レタ日ノ事
On a clear, sunny day,
魔法以上のユカイが限りなく降りそそぐ
a joy beyond magic pours down endlessly.
不可能じゃないわ明日また会うとき
It's not impossible. When we meet again tomorrow,
笑いながらハミング 嬉しさを集めよう
laughing and humming, let's gather up our happiness.
カンタンなんだよこんなの 追いかけてねつかまえてみて
It's easy like this! Chase after it, try to catch it—
大きな夢&夢好きでしょう?
big dreams & you love dreams, right?
イロイロ予想ができそうでできないミライ それでもひとつだけ分かるよ
Various predictions seem possible yet impossible, but there's one thing I know for sure!
ふー、しんどいわー
Whew, that's exhausting!
いきなり始まるじゃん
It started so suddenly!
一休みすろぜ
Let's take a break.
疲れたな
I'm tired.
初めてだぞ
This is a first.
え、最初から、なにこれ、いきなり何、まださ、10分も経ってないぞ
Huh? From the beginning, what is this? What's going on, not even 10 minutes have passed yet!
そう。いや、我々お姉さん組だからさ、しょうがない
Yeah. Well, we're the "older sisters" group, so it can't be helped.
お姉さん組つうのはね、ちょっと待ってね、ちょっと息が整ってから喋るね
Being the older sisters group means... wait, let me catch my breath before I speak.
踊りたかったんでしょ?
You wanted to dance, didn't you?
え、せ、あ、ねぇ、性的満足しちゃう、やばい、やだ、やだ
Huh? S-Ah, hey... sexual satisfaction... yikes, no, no!
いや、ぎょ、だよ、やじゃねぇ
No, y-yikes, not "no"!
いうことでね、はい、我々ね、ちょっと、待って、我々、そんな全力で歌って踊ってたのか?
Anyway, yes! Were we really singing and dancing with all our might?
我々集まりました、どうですか?
We've gathered together, how is it?
ついに集まったこのお姉さん組の姿を、存分に堪能してください
Please fully enjoy the sight of this older-sisters group finally gathered.
まぁね、存分に堪能させてはやらん
Well, I won't let you fully enjoy it!
いや、緊張さとかさ、ほら、見てみて、かわいいよね
The nervousness and all, look, look, isn't it cute?
かわいい、ちっちゃ、なんてだっけ?これ
Cute, tiny, what was it again? This.
はい、あ、囚われた、拘束された、拘束されて、助けてね
Yes, ah, captured, restrained, restrained, help me!
あの、三人揃ってやりたかったことがこれなのかんだ
So this was what the three of us wanted to do together?
いやいやいや、でもさ
No, no, no, but still...
あ、我々さ、ちょっと待って、腕が、あ、縛られてる! あ、やだ、話してください
Ah, wait, our arms are, ah, tied up! Ah, no, let us go!
ノエルと、あ、フロアだった
Noel and... ah, it was Flare!
そんで、なんでだ、あ、治った治った、よかったよかった
And why was that? Ah, it's fixed, good, good!
は、なんだっけ、そんで、あ、そうそうそう
Ha, what was it? And then, ah, right, right, right.
で、あのですね、いや、今さ、みんなさ、あの、だいじょーぶ、あ、大丈夫か、手にかけだけどまだ10分も経ってないんだぞ
And well, now everyone, are you okay? Ah, is it okay? We started, but not even 10 minutes have passed yet!
楽しいな、楽しい、楽しい
It's fun, fun, fun!
あのね、コメントの皆さんもうお気づきだと思うんですけれども、いや我々ね、あのハレ晴レユカイをね、1番しか歌って踊ってないっていうのにね、ぶっ倒れるこの体力のなさ!
And you know, everyone in the comments probably noticed, we sang and danced "Hare Hare Yukai" for only the first chorus and we're already collapsing from lack of stamina!
いや、ホロライブこれからね、どんどん歌って踊ってアイドルになっていくんですよ
Hololive is going to sing and dance and become idols from here on!
うんうん、そうだね。そんな中で、そんな中でね、デラミングよ
Yeah, yeah, that's right. Amidst that, amidst that, Delamingu!
はい、構わす
Yes, don't worry about it.
え、なんだっけ?あ、そう、そんな、そんなが、こんな体力じゃやってられないだろうと、ね、後輩にも示しがつきません
Huh, what was it? Ah, right, with such stamina we can't keep going, and it won't set a good example for our juniors!
ピチピチのね、小虫たちに、我々がね、できるところを見せなくては、ということでね、今日はどうするかっていうと
To the fresh, bubbly juniors, we have to show them what we can do, so today what are we going to do?
うん、我々の、自分の苦手克服をしましょう
Yeah, let's overcome our weaknesses!
お!
Oh!
我々、基本的人権はなんですけど、そんな名前は、アイドラメとして、体力測定!
Wait, as idols, physical fitness testing!
えーむ、団長毎日、なんかく、トレーニングしてるからさ、別に入らない気がする
Noel-dancho trains every day, so I feel like she doesn't really need it.
あの、言ってな?マジで。あ、そっか。
Did you say that? Seriously. Ah, I see.
できる?わー
Can you? Whoa.
いやいやいや、そんな言てたら弾けいちゃうよ。いいのいいの。
No, no, no, if you say that, you'll burst. It's fine, it's fine.
これ、運動場移動してるじゃん。あ、じゃあ、ジャンプで移動しよう? せーの、いで。行くよ。
We're moving to the athletic field. Ah, then let's move by jumping! Ready, go. Here we go.
イェーイ すげえ!
Yay! Amazing!
あ、ちょっと船長、ちょっと、重い!
Ah, Captain, wait, it's heavy!
体力測定! あれでよっか、はれはれ踊るわ
Physical fitness test! Let's dance hare hare with that.
でもさ、よくね、もう帰ろうぜ
But you know, let's just go home already!
あ、でも今なんかせっかく、待って待って待って待って また
Ah, but now since we went through the trouble... wait, wait, wait, wait! Again...
ころころころころころころ!
Rolling rolling rolling!
またなんか。いやいやいや、帰らせんよ。
Again something... No, no, no, I won't let you go home!
帰らせませんと。
I won't let you go home.
ちょっと、待って腕これ、戻すね。 5節はこれ治ると。
Wait, let me fix this arm. Section 5 fixes this.
あほら、なおった。 直ったね、直った。よし。
Ah look, it's fixed. It's fixed, it's fixed. Great.
ちょっと前や、前や。今日折れてる日。
Let's go forward. Today is a broken day.
はい、えーっとですね、体力測定をやって、誰か仕切ってくんない?ちょっと疲れちゃった。あ、オッケーオッケー。
Yes, um, doing the physical fitness test... can someone take charge? I'm a bit tired. Ah, okay okay.
体力測定をするんだよね?
We're doing a physical fitness test, right?
そうなんだけど、待って。
That's right, but wait.
そう、なんかいまから、やっぱね、うちらいどるだから、アイドルって、ただ歌うだけじゃなく体力もね、ダンスで踊ったりするから色々さ、で
Yeah, like, from now on, since we're idols, idols don't just sing, they also have stamina for dancing and stuff... so, and
自分たちのね、やっぱそういう体力って測定したことないんだよね。 ある?
we've never actually measured our stamina like that. Have you?
あ、まあ、体力測定とかはあるかもしれないけどさ。
Ah, well, physical fitness tests might exist, but...
最近ない。お互いに。
Not recently. Mutually.
マリンが主役だからでも今日ね。そうだね。バイバイ!
But Marine is the main character today, right? That's right. Bye-bye!
ちょっと、うみえさんから画面が以降って言われた。
Wait, Umie-san told us the screen is moving over.
ちょっとね、邪魔だったみたい。
It seems I was a bit in the way.
まあ だから ちょっと まあお姉さん組のちょっと体力
So, we're gonna measure the physical strength
というかさ、そう数値がどんぐらいのものかっていうのを
of the older-sister group, to see what kind of numbers we get...
ちょっと測っていこうかって。
We're going to measure it.
そうね。思ってます。うん、そうそうそうそう。
That's right. Yes, exactly.
まず我々が お手本みたいな感じなのかな？
First, are we supposed to be the role models?
あ、そうなのよ。なんか、おい！お手本とは偉そうだな！
Ah, that's right. Wait, calling us role models sounds pretty arrogant!
だってマリン最初やったのなんかね、もう うん、何？
Because Marine, the first time you did it, you were like... What?
何が言いたいのか？
What are you trying to say?
いや だって恥ずかしいのが恥をかくのが
I mean, the embarrassing thing is making a fool of yourself.
いや むしろ恥をかかせたいなと思って。
No, I actually want to make you embarrass yourself.
え そうだ え、待て、待て待て、めぐめぐめぐめぐめぐ！ごめん！ごめん！ごめん！待て待て待て！
Eh? Wait, wait, wait, Meg! Sorry! Sorry! Sorry! Wait, wait, wait!
やめろ！やめろ！
Stop it! Stop it!
やめろ！やめろ！一発！一発！
Stop! One hit! One hit!
あ、コケちゃった。よっしゃ！おし、終わった。
Ah, I tripped. Alright! Done.
はい、じゃあ 何からやる？
Okay, then what do we do first?
え と これ メニューってこれ一気にバーってって 一個ずつ行った方がいいのかな？
Uh, as for the menu, should we go through them one by one all at once?
いや、一個ずつ行く？
Yeah, go one by one?
じゃあ 1個目 今 来るみたい。お、発表！
Then, the first one seems to be coming up. Oh, announcement!
わかった。じゃ、ノルだ。
Got it. Then, Noel.
だから だから だから ドラマティックしよう。ちょっと、じゃあ、フレーアね。フラメンコステップをボイス付きで。
So, let's make it dramatic. Flare, flamenco step with voice!
うたうた。え？
Sing, sing. Eh?
発表！
Announcement!
どことこ どこどこ どこどこ どこどこ行くぞ！どことこ 行きますよ みんなで どんどん！
Dokotoko, doko doko, doko doko, let's go! Dokotoko, everyone going dong-don!
いや、ちょっと待て。
Wait a second.
えっ、これ 言わないってないの？
Eh, isn't there no rule against not speaking?
あ、言わないとダメなの？
Ah, do I have to speak?
あ、もう言ってください。
Ah, just say it.
え、マリンさんとは全然気が合わないね。
Marine-san and I really don't match.
ええと、はい！第1メニューはこちら！「反復横跳び」となって、反復横跳び！反復横跳び！
Um, yes! The first menu is here! 'Side-to-side jumps'! Side-to-side jumps!
船長の国では 反復、反復横跳び。
In the Captain's country, side-to-side jumps.
反復横跳び！
Side-to-side jumps!
イエーイ！
Yay!
え、誰？じゃあさ、そのさ、一番自信あるのさ、誰なの？ちなみに。
Who? So, who's the most confident? By the way.
え、でもノエルでしょ？
Eh, but Noel, right?
いや だって 団長ね 土曜日にね プランクとかめちゃくちゃしたから 筋肉痛になっちゃって
I mean, Danchou did planks and stuff like crazy on Saturday, so I got sore muscles.
はい、言い訳始まりました。
Yes, the excuses have started.
いや、本当 きっついね。なんかおばあちゃんだから
No, it's really tough. Like, because I'm an old lady...
あ、船長も1時間しか寝てねえから。くうっ！
Ah, the captain only slept for 1 hour too. Ku!
分かった、じゃあ団長から、え、どうする？フレア、から行く？
Understood. Then from Danchou, eh, what should we do? Flare, will you go?
え、じゃ、いいよ、私が最初にやるよ。
Eh, fine, I'll go first.
じゃあ、フレアの あの、平均、平均女性の体力を見せtaro。
Then Flare, show us the physical strength of an average woman.
なんかね 平均があって、その平均に我々がちゃんと行けるのかどうかっていうのをね、しっかり測っていきたいと思います。はい。
It seems there's an average, and we want to measure properly whether we can reach that average. Yes.
平均行くぞなら、ちょっとじゃあ1回フレーアの結果見てから平均と比べてみますか？
If we're going for the average, shall we check Flare's result first and compare it with the average?
そうだね。
That's right.
では どうします？
Then, what shall we do?
フレア、じゃあ準備よかったら。
Flare, if you're ready.
はい、大丈夫です。
Yes, I'm fine.
それでは、フレアの反復横跳び、反復横跳び。
Now, Flare's side-to-side jumps.
さ、スタート。
Now, start.
え、いいの？
Eh, is it okay?
はい。
Yes.
あ、来て。ねえ見て、ポニーテ、ポニーテイルすげえ！
Ah, come. Hey look, ponytail is amazing!
ねえ、伸びてる伸びてる。後ろから見てみ。足なんか不気味。
Hey, it's stretching. Look at it from behind. The legs look spooky.
なあ。これ、見せられた後にちょっとやるの、ねえ？え、なんかちょっと待って、船長が顔埋めるの後ろに立とう。軽やかだ。
Right. Doing it after seeing this, right? Hey, wait, Captain, let's stand behind burying our face. It's light.
ノエル もうちょい前に立ってくれる？お、前？
Noel, could you stand a bit more forward? Oh, in front?
あ、逆にすんな ちょっと成長、長いな。お？こっちにいく？長いな。
Ah, do the opposite. Captain, it's long. Oh? Going this way? It's long.
これ フレアは何回ですか？
Flare, how many times was that?
ちょっと見せてもらえますか？
Can you show us?
何回？
How many times?
もしかして誰も数え てない？
Did nobody count?
え？
Eh?
え、待っ、ごめん。あ、うちか、うち数える感じ？
Eh, wait, sorry. Ah, us, are we supposed to count?
いや、なんか今テクリさん、あの、なんか数えてくれてるのかな？
No, it seems Tekuri-san is counting for us?
あ、時間を測ってくれてたのか。
Ah, so she was measuring the time.
時間しか測られてなかった。フレアでも、なんかもう1回やれと言いそうだな、なんか。
Only the time was measured. Flare, you look like you're about to say let's do it again.
あ、じゃ、ちょっとフレア、1回休憩、休憩挟もう。じゃあ、
Ah, then Flare, let's take a break. Then,
次に行くか。
shall we go next?
ノエル行く？じゃあ、ちょっと、数えるのは任せな。
Noel, will you go? Then, leave the counting to me.
えっとな、待って。これさ、あのさ、線を越えるたびに1とすればいいの？
Wait. For this, every time we cross the line, we count as 1?
うんうん。
Yeah, yeah.
1、2、3かな？
1, 2, 3?
オッケーオッケー。
Okay, okay.
でもなんかスタッフさんも、あ、なんか、あれじゃなくて、スタッフさんが数えるみたいです。
Wait, the staff seems to be counting instead.
はい、じゃあスタート言ってください。
Yes, please say start.
はい。
Yes.
スタート！
Start!
おッ おッ なんか軽やかじゃない？
Oh, oh, isn't it light?
お、軽やか。
Oh, light.
え、待て。あ、さ、そんなブルブルされたら我が輩のチャンネルが、我がチャンネルが
Eh, wait. If you shake like that, our channel...
性的満足、おー！
Sexual satisfaction, oh!
なる、え、なんで？ほっ！
How come? Ho!
大丈夫かこれ？
Is this okay?
見てる分には早いね。
Watching it, it's fast.
早いね。
It's fast.
はい。
Yes.
おおー！速そう！
Ooh! Looks fast!
え、すごくない？めちゃくちゃ、今うまかったと思うんだけど。
Eh, isn't it amazing? I think I did really well just now.
え、今何回？45回？
Eh, how many times now? 45 times?
お、45回！
Oh, 45 times!
え、すごくない？
Eh, isn't that amazing?
え、平均してないよ？
Eh, didn't it reach the average?
でも50回じゃなきゃ平均って。なんか平均50って出たかも知れん。
But the average is supposed to be 50. Maybe the average was 50.
うわあ！
Whoa!
マジ？悔しい。
Really? Frustrating.
50じゃないの？悔しくない？
Isn't it 50? Isn't it frustrating?
ノエル、じゃあフレアやる？
Noel, then Flare, will you do it?
いいよ。先やって。
Sure. Go ahead.
ちょっと待って。
Wait a minute.
え、待て。あのさ、こう行って、こう行って、この、この足はこっち行くの？いか、いかないでこうやっていく
Eh, wait. Like, going like this, going like this, does this foot go this way? No, without going, going like this...
え、やったことあるよね？ある。
Eh, you've done this before, right? Yes.
こう、こう行って、こう行ったら、こう、こう行って、こう行って、こう行って、そう、こう行って、こう行って、こう行って。あ、そうそうそうそう。オッケーオッケー。
Like this, like this, going like this, like this, like this, yeah, like this, like this, like this. Ah, yeah, yeah, yeah. Okay, okay.
じゃ、ここからね。
Then from here, right?
うん。右行くの？
Yeah. Going right?
どっちからでもいいよ。分かった。よし。
Either way is fine. Understood. Alright.
では
Now then...
え、マリン船長
Uh, Captain Marine,
生かしていただきます。
I'll let you take it away.
それではいきます。
Here we go.
がんばれ、がんばれ。
Do your best, do your best!
スタート！
Start!
え、待って待って！
Wait, wait, wait!
え、なにこれ、ちょっとなにこれ
What is this? Hey, what is this?
待て、急げ急げ！
Wait, hurry up, hurry up!
急がなきゃ、急がなきゃ！
I gotta hurry, I gotta hurry!
よしよしよし、待て待て待て！
Okay, okay, wait, wait, wait!
あれ、なんか違う、あれ、なんか違う！
Huh, something's wrong, wait, something's wrong!
なにが違うの？待って、待って！
What's different? Wait, wait!
なにかが違うな、待て、ジャンプだ！
Something's off, wait, it's a jump!
ジャンプ、ジャンプ！
Jump, jump!
あ、そうそうそうそう！
Ah, right, right, right!
あ、ジャンプか！待て、やばい！
Ah, a jump? Wait, no way!
やばいやばい、足おかしい、足！
No way, my legs feel weird!
おかしい、おかしい、おかしい、おかしい！
It's weird, weird, weird, weird!
おかしい、おかしい、おかしい！
Weird, weird, weird!
なんかバタバタしてる！
I'm flapping all over the place!
23回？
23 times?
え？
Eh?
若い！
You're young!
Young!
23歳ではないんだぞ？
You're not 23, are you?
ああ、
Ah,
ではではない。
not that.
歳ではない。
Not my age.
あ、なるほど。
Ah, I see.
ま、ママママ、ママママ。
Well, well, well, well.
ま、でも、たぶんこれ小学生くらいのさ、もんで。
Well, but this is probably elementary school level.
これそうなんだよ、23回って何歳ぐらいなんだろうね？
I wonder what age 23 times corresponds to?
マリン小学生だから。
Marine's an elementary schooler, so.
あ、じゃあ若い。
Ah, then you're young.
うん。
Yeah.
逆の若さをアピールした。
Appealing with fake youth.
たたた！
Tatta!
な、そういうことね。
Ah, I see.
ふうたんやって、ふうたん。
Fuutan, go ahead.
もう一回、もう一回。
One more time, one more time.
さあ、がんばれ！
Come on, do your best!
がんばれ、がんばれ！
Good luck, good luck!
いや、だっても、ポニーテールするずっと
No, but your ponytail is constantly...
て、きもい！
Gross!
はっ！
Huh?
なんで？
Why?
かたい！
So stiff!
やめて、やめて！
Stop it, stop it!
はい。
Right.
二回目というハンデを背負って、がんばれ！
Bearing the handicap of going second, do your best!
ね、がんばれ、でもすごい！
Right, do your best, but that's amazing!
早いよ！
You're fast!
軽いよ、軽いよ、軽いよ！
You're so light, so light, so light!
ポニーテール揺れてるよ！
Your ponytail is swaying!
はい、はい、はい！
Yes, yes, yes!
チャリで来た、みたいなね。
Like you came on a bicycle.
がんばれ！
Do your best!
足上がんない！
Your legs aren't lifting!
がんばれ！ミリも上がんない足！
Do your best! Your legs aren't even lifting a millimeter!
がんばれ！がんばれ！
Do your best! Do your best!
がんばれ！
Do your best!
ふうたん、お疲れ！
Fuutan, great job!
なんか、おー、53！
Whoa, 53!
え、一回目とこれすごいよ！
Wait, compared to the first time, that's amazing!
すごいよ、そうだよ！
That's amazing, right?
一回目で、しかもその中でそのスコアはすごい！
Getting that score on the first try is amazing!
え、ちなみに、
By the way...
うん、平均って？
What's the average?
50、
50...
50？
50?
50なの？
Is it 50?
うん。
Yeah.
それ50なんですか？
Is that really 50?
上さん？
Ue-san?
平均値は、
The average is...
ええ、
Uh...
10代女性は平均45回。
For teenage women, the average is 45 times.
あ、男性。
Ah, men.
平均の、
The average...
アベレージ。
Average.
あ、でも船長！
Ah, but Captain!
あ、やだ！
Oh no!
なんか6歳の平均が20、なんか3回？
It says the average for 6-year-olds is 20-something times?
うん、6歳なんだ。
Yeah, 6 years old.
あんまり25回ぐらいだったって、それ平均値下回ってんじゃないか？
It was only about 25 times, doesn't that mean you're below average?
なに？うそじゃない！
What? No way!
次もあるから。
There's still next time.
うん、あるある。
Yeah, there is.
あ、確かにはね。
Ah, that's true.
次、次ってこと次。
Next, next, then next.
なんだったっけ？
What was it again?
あ、じゃあ次のやっていきますか、じゃあ。
Ah, shall we do the next one then?
まあね、これが反復横跳びでしたと。
Well, that was the side hop test.
よし、じゃ。
Alright then.
ほいっと。
Hoick.
じゃ、次やっていくのはね、
So the next one we're doing is...
こちら。
This one.
こちらです、えっと、バランス測定！
Here it is, uh, balance measurement!
なんだよ、これ私やばいかも。
Oh no, I might be bad at this.
これね、
This is...
うんうん。
Yeah.
あのね、目を閉じて片足でどれだけ立っていられるかっていう。
You close your eyes and see how long you can stand on one foot.
ああ、それは秒数で？
Ah, is it based on seconds?
じゃあみんな一斉にやってさ、
Then let's all do it at the same time,
倒れた人からマグマに落とさせてね。
and whoever falls drops into the lava.
あれ？
Huh?
マリーはこれ体力関係ない気がするから。
Marine probably doesn't need physical strength for this.
バランスでしょ？
It's balance, right?
うん。
Yeah.
いいんじゃないか？
Shouldn't it be fine?
いけるんでしょ？
You can do it, right?
バランスボウルのマリンって言われてっからさ。
Since they call you the balance ball Marine.
初めて聞いたわ！
First time I've heard that!
そんななってんじゃねえよ。
Don't just make things up.
え、ちなみに、あの、あれね、
By the way, uh,
落ちた人からね、マグマに落ちたと思ってね、
the person who falls first, imagine you fell into lava,
あの、マグマに落ちたときの声出してね。
and make the sound of falling into lava.
わかった。
Got it.
じゃあ、えっと、
Well, um...
始める？
Should we start?
うん。
Yeah.
じゃあ、行くよ？
Here we go, ready?
うん。
Yeah.
船長、
Captain,
どうぞよろしくお願いします。
we're in your hands.
それではいきます。
Here we go.
3、
3,
2、
2,
1、
1,
はい、目閉じて。
Close your eyes.
ちょっともうだめか。
I guess I'm done for.
大丈夫大丈夫。
You're fine, you're fine.
まだ大丈夫、立ってる限りは。
You're still fine as long as you're standing.
立ってる限りは生きている。
As long as you're standing, you're alive.
立ってるから大丈夫、立ってますから。
You're standing, so it's fine, you're standing.
なんかすっごいどったんばったん聞こえるよ。
I hear all sorts of clattering noises.
あ、それ？
Ah, that?
それ、ケモノフレンズ。
That's Kemono Friends.
ちょっと待って。
Hold on.
待て、おつとこ？
Wait, staying balanced?
1回おつとこ。
Let's keep our balance.
待て、あのさ、足、足じゃないの？
Wait, isn't it about your legs?
足、足に、
Your legs...
あ、待て、あ、そう！
Ah, wait, oh!
これさ、足に重心？
This, putting your weight on your legs...
いけるんじゃな、あ、待て、やばい、いきそう！
Can you do it? Wait, oh no, I'm about to go!
あ、ごめん！待て、やばい、やばい！
Ah, sorry! Wait, no, no!
何？やばい！
What? Oh no!
はじめ！やめろ、やめろ、やめろお前！
Start! Stop it, stop it, stop it you!
ごめん、やめろお前！
Sorry, stop it you!
ちょっと待って、生きそう！
Wait a second, I'm gonna make it!
なに？生きそう！
What? You'll make it!
もう立っといてよお前！
Just stay standing, hey!
ちょっとどっかいけ！
Get away somewhere!
せめて生きて！
At least survive!
せめて生きてて！
At least stay alive!
熱い！
It's hot!
あつい、あつい！
Hot, hot!
熱い！
Hot!
うわあ、熱い！
Whoa, it's hot!
熱い！
Hot!
うわあ、熱い！
Whoa, it's hot!
あ、船長死んだ、死んだ、死ぬ！
Ah, Captain died, died, she's dead!
死ぬ、死ぬ！
She's dead, she's dead!
一緒に、一緒にね。
Together, let's go together.
一緒にいこうね。
Let's go together.
なんだこいつら。
What are these guys?
まあ、2度と呼んでやんねえからな！
Well, I'm never inviting you guys again!
やんねえからよ！
I won't!
はい。
Yes.
呼んでくれよ。
Please invite us.
はい、呼んでくれよお！
Yes, please invite me!
あれ、結局さ、どうだったんだよ？
Wait, how did it turn out in the end?
ノエル、ちょっとやめてよ。
Noel, stop it.
人のノエルで。
Using Noel's...
フレアが30秒。
Flare got 30 seconds.
船長は33秒。
Captain got 33 seconds.
ノエルは？
And Noel?
おっ。
Oh.
すげえ。
Amazing.
あ、50秒？
Ah, 50 seconds?
あ、50秒ぐらい。船長あきら、いや、
Ah, about 50 seconds. Captain gave u— no,
違うよ、フレア、フレアとチンジュしたんだ。
Wait, Flare, Flare panicked with me.
なんか、あきらめ、あきらめてね、私のも一緒に死んだらしい。
Like, you gave up, and apparently you died along with mine.
マリンが泣き散らかしてる。
Marine is freaking out crying.
ごめん、ごめん、きんきんじゃん。
Sorry, sorry, you're whining!
よかった、まだあるか。
Good thing there's still more.
まだある、まだあるの？
Still more, is there still more?
バランス測定はまあ、こんな感じでね。
Well, that's what the balance measurement was like.
まあ、そんな感じだったということで。
Well, something like that.
やでも、なんだろうね、これね、なんか…
Yeah, but I wonder what this is...
なんか、なんだろうね。ルックスのね、コツが掴め、最後の方ね、覚醒しそうだった。
I wonder what it is. It felt like I was finally getting the hang of the posture.
あ、でもなんかすごい突っかい出してきだもんね。
Ah, but it started getting really awkward, right?
え？ウソでしょ？
Eh? No way!
私よ。思ったの。足じゃ、足じゃなくて、そう、足、足じゃなくて…
I thought, it's not the legs, not the legs, but...
重心、重心が足じゃなくてね、コアマッスルなの。
Center of gravity, it's not your legs, it's your core muscles!
あ、ここ！ここで立つとね、立てる。あ、本当ね！なるほど！
Ah, right here! If you stand here, you can stand. Ah, really! I see!
気づいた。今後、みんな参考にしてよ、本当。
I noticed. Everyone, use this as a reference from now on.
次行こっか。
Let's go to the next one.
次はですね…
Next is...
こちらです。プランク、腹筋ローラー。
This one: Plank, Ab Roller.
ああ、そっか、なんかプランクしたことあるから、腹筋ローラー初めてでちょっと…
Ah, I've done planks before, but it's my first time with an ab roller...
腹筋ローラーがね、実談ね、あの…これね、船長への、お誕生日プレゼントでいただいたものだし…
The ab roller is actually a birthday present given to the Captain...
あ、一味も心配しとるよ。
Ah, the "Ichimi" are worried too.
今日ね、あのプレゼントを、あの、拝見しましたところこちら入ってましたので、ぜひともね、今日ちょっとこれやってみたいなということで…
When I checked the present today, this was inside, so I wanted to try it out today...
おお、なるほど！
Oh, I see!
ということにいたしました。
So that's how it turned out.
え、誰からやる？
Eh, who's going first?
じゃあ私からやる。
Then I'll go first.
おっ、ナイス！
Oh, nice!
みんな、ね、率先してね。
Everyone's being so proactive.
見せててね。
Show us.
そう、これね、めっちゃ難しくて、あのちょっとね、我々もね、裏でやろうとしたんだけど、みんなねペタンペタン倒れて…
Yeah, this is super difficult, and we tried doing it backstage too, but everyone just flopped...
100回できたら、横向いてやろうか。見やすいようにね。
If you can do 100 times, let's do it sideways so it's easier to see.
じゃあ、うちらは離れよう。
Then, let's step back.
うん。最強のやつ見せてやろう。
Yeah. Let's show them the strongest one.
なんか強気な。
Sounds pretty confident.
はい、じゃあですね、ちょっとみなさんには見えづらい、VTuberにしか見えない腹筋ローラーでコロコロやっていくわけですけど。
Alright, we're going to use the VTuber-exclusive ab roller and roll away.
マジある腹筋ローラー。
There really is an ab roller.
はい、あ、やってるやってる。あ…！
Yeah, she's doing it. Ah...!
いや、そんなマンガみたいな…マジ…？
No, like something out of a manga... Seriously?
ずこっ…！
Slump...!
ずこっ！
Slump!
これね、やって…！
Doing this...
腹筋、腹筋ローラー！
Ab roller!
やって、待って、待って。
Do it, wait, wait.
え、じゃあ、団長？
Eh, then, Dancho?
え、じゃあノエル、ノエル。
Eh, then Noel, Noel.
じみよ。
Show us.
ペタン…！
Plop...!
ノエル、1回でも頑張れ、1回でも。
Noel, do your best for at least one time.
え、いけるか？え、これ、こうやってまっすぐだよよね？
Eh, can I do it? You keep it straight, right?
こういって、良い姿勢で、お、いいぞ、ちょっとノエル、ちょっと…！
Like this, with good posture, oh, looking good, wait Noel...！
ああー！いっちゃった、いっちゃった…！あ、ダメだ、もうダメだ！
There she went...! Ah, no good, no good anymore!
セーフ、セーフ、まっすぐ、どこまで…、待って待って、やばいやばい！
Safe, safe, straight, how far... wait, oh no!
おにぎりご飯ね。
Onigiri rice, huh.
腹筋にダメージが…
Damage to the abs...
え、でもこれすごいハードル低いんじゃない？だってまだ…
Eh, but isn't the hurdle super low for this? Because still...
1回とかしかみんなできてないからこれ船長1回でもできればスターになれる。
Everyone can only do it once, so if Captain can do even once, you can become a star.
ねえ、なんかこれすごいあれ思い出すわ。あのさ、船長がさ、戦国時代にジムに通ってた頃…
This really reminds me of when Captain went to the gym in the Sengoku period...
あの、じいちゃんバーチャルしか周りにいなくて、スウィミング行ったらね、船長が一番早かったの。
There were only grandpa virtuals around, and when I went swimming, Captain was the fastest.
じいちゃんバーチャルしかいねえから、一番だよ。
Since there were only grandpa virtuals, I was number one.
そうそう、見せて、見せてみてそれを。今この低レベルな戦いの中 最強を見せつけ…
Show us that. Now, amidst this low-level battle, show us the strongest...
いや、早く見せろ、どこまで…！いやま、この線まで行かなきゃダメだから。
No, hurry and show us how far...! You have to go up to this line.
あんまり、ちょっと、きわどいな。
That's a bit too risky.
スターになれたか…？まっすぐだったね、大丈夫。
Did you become a star...? It was straight, it's alright.
よいしょ…！起きよう。
Heave-ho...! Let's get up.
え、これもうやんの？お、これは…おしまい。
Eh, are we done? Oh, this is... done.
ノエル、ノエルさんが1位。
Noel-san is number one.
あれはもうちょっといきたかった。1回でいいってマジ？これ。
I wanted to go a bit further. Is it seriously just one time?
なんか情けないけど、1回を越えるのが難しいんだよ。
It's pathetic, but surpassing even one time is so difficult.
いやいやなんかこれはね是非ともホロライブのみんなにも挑戦してほしい。
I definitely want everyone in Hololive to try this.
我々がね1回しか1回もできなかったからさ、この低レベルな戦い更新してほしいよ。
Since we couldn't even do more than once, I want you guys to update this.
更新してくれみんな、運動に自信ねえ子たち更新してくれ。
Update it, those who aren't confident in sports.
さあ、次はですね、こちらですね、はい。
Now, next is this one.
長座体前屈。
Seated forward bend.
これふれあ知らないらしいじゃん。
Flare apparently doesn't know this.
え、どうやってやるの？
Eh, how do you do it?
回して…こう？違う。こうこうこう。
Rotate... like this? No. Like this.
あ、直ったんじゃない？
Ah, didn't it get fixed?
直ったかな？オッケーオッケー。
Did it fix? Okay, okay.
いいねいいね。
Good, good.
長座体前屈ってそれわかる？
Seated forward bend, do you know what that is?
わかんない。
I don't know.
これね、なんか今ね、あの皆さんには見えないですけど、ここに箱が、ボードバーチャルのね、そこバーチャルのお箱があってですね、ここにあのセンチが書いてあって、この箱をここからこうやってずっとこうやってやって、そのセンチを競うというものです。はいはい。
Right now, there's a virtual box here with centimeters written on it, and you slide it to compete.
柔軟性ですね、要するにね。
Flexibility, in other words.
なるほど柔軟性。
I see, flexibility.
これも横じゃなくて大丈夫？
Is it okay if this isn't sideways either?
これ横の方が確かに見栄えいいかもね。みんなに見やすい。
Side view might actually look better. Easier for everyone to see.
見やすいよね、どれだけ曲がったかが。
Easy to see how much they bent.
だから、横、横に、フレアじゃなくて、横でやっててもらえます？
So, can you do it sideways, Flare?
お、ありがとうございます。
Oh, thank you very much.
ありがとうございます、恐れ入ります。
Thank you, I'm humbled.
じゃあじゃあ…
Then...
できましたと。誰から？やれる？船長無理だわ、今。じゃあ、じゃあノエルちゃん手本見せて。
Done. Captain can't do it now. Noel-chan, show us an example.
じゃあノエルちゃんお手本よ。
Noel-chan, show us an example.
じゃあ男爵もそんな…
Dancho is also...
あれ治ったじゃん。
Your legs got better, didn't they?
いよっ。身体は、ねえ。
Heave-ho. My body is...
腹筋ローラーで結構疲れてるって話だったけどさ。
You said you were pretty tired from the ab roller, though.
あの、柔軟はどうなん？
Um, how about flexibility?
いや、ストレッチとか全然なんだよね。だからちょっとどんぐりかかんないけど、とりあえずやってみます。
I don't really stretch at all. So I'll just try it for now.
最初うえはまあね…
At first, well...
あ、これはね、そう、2回測って、良い記録の方をゲットすればいいわけなので、だから…
You measure twice and take your better record, so...
1回ずつをこうやってって、2人やろう、オッケー。
Let's do it one by one, okay.
ノエル、がんばれ。
Noel, do your best.
ノエルの技は盗むね？
I'm gonna steal Noel's technique, okay?
来ます。
Here it comes.
うん、じゃあ。い、い、い、い、い、い、
Yeah, then... go, go, go...
なるほど。
I see.
あ、やわらかいね。
Ah, you're flexible.
どうだ？ノエルそれさ、なんかさ、おっぱい邪魔そうだななんか。
How's that? Noel, your boobs look like
they're in the way.
おっぱいがこ、ちょ、こ、
My boobs are g-, wait, g-
見てんじゃねえよ！
Don't look!
と、取ってあげようか。
Should I push them out of the way?
なんか、だ、長71.5？
Wait, 71.5 cm?
お、え、いいのかないくって。
Is this good or not?
平均が分からない。
I don't know the average.
最後に平均聞こうよ、じゃあ。そうだな。
Let's hear the average at the end. Right.
あ、結果、そうだな。じゃあもう1回？
Shall we do it one more time?
え、ちょっとじゃ、1回交替して、
Um, then let's switch places for a bit,
そうそう。あの、周りの記録を見て、より上を目指すのよ。
Check everyone else's records
and aim higher.
なるほど、なるほど。
I see, I see.
さあ。
Now then,
初めての、お、お、どんどん、どんどん。お、乗ってきた？リズム、ビート刻んじゃう？
Are you getting into the rhythm?
Keeping the beat?
さあ、フレアちゃんの記録。
Now, Flare's record.
行きます。
Here we go.
息を吐きながら行くとね、よくいけるらしい。
Apparently if you exhale while doing it,
you can go further.
なるほど。
I see.
すーって。はい、吸って、すー。
Like "suuu". Inhale, "suuu".
はい、すー。
And "suuu".
ここまで？すごい。
This far? Amazing!
え、いいんじゃない？
Eh, isn't that good?
記録は？あ、47.7！
What's the record? Ah, 47.7!
すごい、やわらかい。
Amazing, so flexible!
負けてらんないわよ。
I can't afford to lose.
フレアが一番体が柔らかくなってる今。
Flare's body is at its
most flexible right now.
マリンが、いや、マリンは絶対柔らかくないかもしれない。
Marine might definitely
not be flexible.
いや、言っとくけど、船長は今日ピッ、ピップ、エレキバンつけてっからね。
I'm wearing Pip Elekibans today, you know.
エレキバン？ダメじゃん！
Elekiban? That's no good!
いや、だって、効く、
No, because it helpsー
え、ちょっとこれ、この位置？よしこうね。
Wait, is this the position? Okay, like this.
よし。待ってね、体を柔らかく。
Okay. Wait, softening my body.
え、ちょっと待って、肩凝りもほうぼうすね。よいしょ。あ、第2部入っちゃったね、ここ。
My stiff shoulders are all over the place.
Ah, we're into part two here.
痛いね。
It hurts.
よし、行くぞ。
All right, let's go.
いけ。
Go!
はあふう、
Haa, fuu...
あでも、頑張ってる。
Ah, but she's trying hard.
もっといける、もっといける。
You can go further,
you can go further!
すごい！
Amazing!
やわらかいよ、もしかして。
You might actually be flexible!
なんで？
Why?!
なんでそんなショボいの？
Why is it so crappy?
70？
70?
え、でもさ、さっきから変わんないぴょ。
Eh, but it hasn't changed since earlier.
あ、そっか。あ、ノエル、ノエル。
Ah, is that so. Ah, Noel, Noel.
測り方、間違ってる？間違ってる？
Is the way of measuring wrong?
Is it wrong?
箱の手前側のさ、え、どっちで測ってた？
On the front side of the box, wait,
which one were you measuring from?
ちょっと、このスタッフのメス掛けに、
Wait, listening to the
staff's measurementsー
やめて、スタッフさんをメス掛けっていうの。
Stop calling the staff's
measurement that!
いや、スタッフのメス掛けが、
No, the staff's measurement is...
ここで、こういって、あ、今ね、あの、
Here, going like this, ah,
right now, um,
あ、確かに。
Ah, true.
あ、ポーズが学生平気、これ、あ、ポーズが、あの、行き過ぎててもおかしいんだ。
Ah, the pose is student-level, wait,
ah, if it goes too far it's weird.
あ、逆にね。
Ah, vice versa.
あ、マイナス30cm。
Ah, minus 30 cm.
オッケー、オッケー、オッケー、オッケー。
Okay, okay, okay, okay.
遠い、あごめん。
Too far—ah, sorry.
ちょっと動かしちゃったかも。大丈夫？
I might have moved it a bit. Are you alright?
変じゃない？平気ですか？ちょっとマイク触っちゃった、ごめんなさい。
Isn't it weird? Are you okay?
I touched the mic, sorry.
船長が30cm切って、41.5。
Captain is under 30cm, 41.5.
はいはいはいはいはい。
Right, right, right, right.
で、フレアが、確か47？
And Flare was, let's see, 47?
で、船長が40？
And Captain was 40?
オッケー。
Okay.
よし、じゃあ第2の記録、さらに上を目指していきますよ。
All right, let's aim even higher
for our second records!
いくぞ。
Let's go.
これいいのかな、結構。
Is this good, pretty much?
え、どうなんだろね。平均楽しみだね。
Eh, I wonder how it is.
Looking forward to the average.
平均気になるね。どれくらいなんだろ。これいいのかな？いい記録なのかな、結構。
Curious about the average. How much is it?
Is this a good record?
さあ、ノエル、意気込みはいかがですか？このみんなの記録を見た結果。
Now, Noel, what are your thoughts?
Seeing everyone's results.
これってさ、呼吸法が大事な気がしてきた。気づいちゃった？気づいちゃった。刃モンの呼吸に気づいちゃった。
I feel like breathing technique is important.
You noticed the breathing of the Blade Demon.
行くぞじゃあ、船長。使っちゃう？
Let's go then, Captain.
Shall we use it?
来ます。がんばりますね。
Here it comes. I'll do my best.
それ。
Hah!
ノエル足真っ直ぐだわ。
Noel's legs are straight.
なんか、の、ノエル、こ、お胸さ、お胸さ、ちょっと抑えてようか？
Noel, wait, your chest, let me hold
your chest down a bit?
お胸抑えようか？
Shall I hold your chest?
腹ら良くないよ。
Abdomen is no good.
あれ？39センチ。あれ？下がってんじゃん。
Huh? 39 cm. Huh?
It went down.
ラマーズ法だめだって。ラマーズ法だめだってくそっ！
Lamaze method is no good.
Damn it!
行くぞ！
Let's go!
ほらほら。
Look, look.
せいっ！
Heave!
Hah!
きらめいて！せいっ！あ、足が。
Shining bright! Hah! Ah, my legs.
さあ、フレアちゃんです。フレアちゃん、今回の意気込みはいかがですか？どのような方法を試される予定ですか？
Now, it's Flare. What is your enthusiasm?
What kind of method will you try?
ちょっとお胸をきゅって引っ込めてみる。
Try pulling in my stomach tightly.
お腹を引っ込め方。なんか、どこまでいってもさ、突っかかって来たら、胸、突っかかって来たらだから、ちょっとできる限りいく。
Stomach pulling-in method. Go as far
as possible if something gets stuck.
マリンが、お胸こうやってしとこか。
Marine will hold your chest like this.
いや確かに、つぶさんとこれ、いくかも。
Yeah, true, if you crush it,
this might work.
うせっ。
Shut up.
じゃあお胸押さえよっか。
Then let's hold your chest down.
じゃあ行きます。
Then, let's go.
はい。
Yes.
やっぱふうなのだね。
Perfume style, right?
ふるふるしてる、ふるふるしてる！
It's shaking, it's shaking!
うい！
Yay!
多分これは、
Probably, this isー
あれですか？35センチ。
Is that so? 35 cm.
み、へいへい！みんなみんな！おる！
Hey hey! Everyone, everyone! Look!
なんで下がっちゃってんの？
Why did it go down?
言っていい？常識の話していい？普通は、こう柔軟けつの、は、2回目の方がいい記録が出るの。はい、これでわかるかな？
Normally, for flexibility, the second time
gives a better record. Understand?
はよやれ。
Hurry up and do it.
なぜだか分かりません、先生。
I don't know why, teacher.
なぜかっていうと、身体がほぐれるから。
Because the body warms up.
待って待って早くして、早すぎでしょ！
Wait, wait, hurry up! Too fast!
開始位置ってさ、どこで測ってんのこれ？
Where is the starting position measured from?
もっともっとこっちからでいいんじゃない？あっ、だめなんだ。
Wouldn't it be better from further this way? Oh, it's no good?
ずるしようとしてるでしょ！頬笑みだめだよ、頬笑みは
You're trying to cheat! No smiling!
違うよ、だって船長一番足短いんだから、もうちょっとこっちにしなよ。
No, because Senchou has the shortest legs, just move it this way.
腕の長さだってよ。マリン、ここだよ、ここ。ここ、ここ、ここ！
Um, arm length too. Marine, it's right here, here, here!
あ、してないですけどね！よし、じゃあ...
Ah, I'm not doing that! Alright, then...
行きますか？じゃあ行くよ。待ってね。頑張れ！頑張れ！
Shall we go? Then I'll go. Wait. Do your best!
そろそろうーん、いっててて...もっといける、もっと！頑張れ！頑張れ！
Slowly... ouch! You can go further, more! Do your best!
どうだ？おっ！
How is it? Oh!
さっきの、おっ、47！
The last one was... oh, 47!
前屈を伸ばしたのは...ほうしょうマリンただ一人。
Houshou Marine was the only one who stretched forward.
スタッフさんいくら払ったの？払っ...ねえ！
Staff, how much did you pay? Paid... Hey!
仲良しだもんね
We're close friends, right?
ほら、不正が...不正の可能性があるぞ。
Look, cheating... There's a possibility of cheating.
ね、このチ...身長が、ええやん。
Hey, this... height is good.
中高生女子の平均がですね、うん、47！
The average for junior and high school girls is 47!
あれ、おかしいな？男女筋肉にステフリステッカーよ。
Wait, that's strange? Stat-free stickers for muscles.
あそね、ちっ、あ、行く！
Ah, right, tsk, ah, go!
ポーズ！筋肉にして、プニプニした身体...
Pose! Making it muscular, that squishy body...
でもこれ筋肉だよ。でもなんか、みんななんで記録下がっちゃったの？
But why did everyone's records drop?
船長は記録伸びちゃった。あ、なんか、そろそろだから。あ、そっか、おそろっち。
Huh, Senchou's record went up. Ah, because it's about time. Matching.
ねえ、ねえ、ねえ、待って待って、泣いたま、泣いちゃった！
Hey, wait, wait, she cried!
だめ！だめよ！あなたの...
No! Your...
あなたの神聖な、大事なところがみえちゃってる！あ、ごめんさい、ごめんさい。
Your sacred, important part is showing! Ah, sorry, sorry.
はいはいはいはい、ということでね、あ、まだあるね。
Yes, yes, yes, yes, so, ah, there's still more.
あ、もうこの次のコーナー行きます？うん、おっ、はい、ということでね、ではね
Ah, shall we go to the next corner? Yes, so, well...
ちょっと次のコーナーに移動、あ、これさ、これさ、あれに行くか、どっち？これに行く感じ？
Moving to the next corner, which one? Feeling like going to this?
こっちね。オッケーです。ということで、はい、体力はね、だいすでし...大したでした。
This way. Okay. So, physical strength was impressive.
ダンスには、体力よりもね、もっと大切なことがあると思うの。
I think there's something more important than physical strength.
それっちょ忘れてたね。あー、あろっ...手振っててた。
You forgot about that, Senchou. Ah, waving.
おっそい！1、2、3、4、5、6、7、8、2、2、3、4、5、6、7、8
So slow! 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8...
アキレス腱伸ばそう。はい、アキレス腱。せーの、1、2、3、4
Let's stretch our Achilles tendons. Yes, ready, 1, 2, 3, 4
もっともっと！5、6、じゃてもっと早くしよう。7、8
More, more! 5, 6, let's make it faster. 7, 8
2、2、3、4、5、6、7、8、はい、のえる！
2, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, yes, Noel!
何の？腰の周りを...うん、ほぐした。
What is this? Loosening around the waist.
で、最後深呼吸ね。はい。すーーー、はーーー、すーーー、はーーー。
And finally, deep breathing. Inhale, exhale.
ということで、ほぐした。では、次のコーナー行きます！はい。
And with that, loosened up. Now, let's go to the next corner!
次の名前は？一心同体グラビア勝負！
Next name? One-Mind Gravure Battle!
もっと大切なこと、それは伝える力ですよ！え、船長はね、表現力が半端なくあるので、体力なんて...体力が必要ないんです。
The more important thing is communication power! Senchou has incredible expressive power, so physical strength isn't needed.
じゃあ表現力で勝負をしましょうか！えっとですね、どんなことをやるのかっていうと...
Then let's compete with expressive power! Let's see, what kind of things will we do...
挑戦者1名と回答者2名に分かれて、挑戦者は似ている三択のお題の中から1つ選び、それをポーズで表現し...
Split into 1 challenger and 2 respondents, choosing a pose from themes.
選択肢があるから、わりとわかりやすいかもしれない。あ、なるほど。ポーズじゃなくてポーズね。
Since there are choices, it might be easy to understand. Not pause, pose.
こうやってやっちゃダメで、ここで、もう...だるまさんがころんだやりたくね？太っと思った。
You can't do it in video like this. Don't you want to play Daruma-san ga koronda?
ぜひね、あの、リスナーの皆さんもち参加してみてくだせい。では、さっそくやってみましょう！
So listeners, try participating too. Let's try it right away!
じゃあ船長から挑戦する？そうだな、ちょびの大...みんな見ようね、みんな見てるから。
Then Senchou will challenge first? Everyone watch, everyone's watching.
われわれ…あ、こっちの耳？あ、こっちの耳
We... Ah, this ear? Ah, this ear.
えー船長ね、じゃあね…
Erm, Captain, right? Then...
はい。
Yes.
え、じゃあ、ちょっとさ、リスナーさんにも教えてあげるね。
Uhm, well, let's tell the listeners too.
えっとね…じゃあね…これにするわ。これ、これ、これ。
Uhm... then... I'll go with this. This, this, this.
では、代表。
Now, representative.
オッケーです。
Okay.
はい、見ていい？見ていいよ。じゃあ…
Yes, can I look? You can look. Then...
それではマリンのポーズ…あ、なんかコメントも見て…マリンのポーズ。
Now Marine's pose... Ah, check the comments too... Marine's pose.
それでは、参ります。
Well then, here we go.
失恋かな？
Could it be heartbreak?
え、キミたちじゃないの？キミたちーってなってる。
Eh, isn't it you guys? Going "You guys~"
結構こたーい、船長ー。
Pretty tough, Captain~
えっと、団長は、じゃあ、もう何も見たくない、もう恋愛なんてしないの失恋で。
Uhm, Danchou's is, like, heartbreak where she won't see anything and won't fall in love ever again.
私、も、なんか、もう恋なんてしないなんて言わないなんて…
I also, like, "I'll never say I'll never fall in love again..."
失恋かな？
Heartbreak?
正解！
Correct!
これが表現力、みんな見習って。
That's expressive power, everyone take notes.
なるほどね。ちゃんと船長今のこの、一瞬でわからせるこの船長の表現力はみんなも見習って。
I see. Everyone should take notes on how the Captain conveyed this in just an instant.
早速挑戦してみてください。
Please try it out right away.
ありあした。なるほど。
Thank you. I see.
じゃあ、ふーたんね？じゃあ私が次やります。
Then, Fuutan? Then I'll go next.
じゃあね、こうだ、こう。
Well then, like this, like this.
どれ、どれ選んでもいいのかな？
Can we pick whichever one?
じゃあ、そうだな、みんなが一番みたそう…なのは、うんと、これかな？これ、これやります。
Well, let's see, what everyone would probably... uhm, is this it? I'll do this one.
オッケー、決まった？
Okay, decided?
うん、だよ。
Yup.
オッケー、見ていいよ。
Okay, you can look.
では、じゃあ行きます。はい。うん、これはかん…これ簡単すぎない？
Well then, here we go. Yes. Hm, isn't this too easy?
これは、これはさすがにわかるよ。
This, this is obviously understandable.
え、でもさ、逆にさ、あれなんじゃないか、初恋にとってこのポーズは恥ずかしいとかさ。
Eh, but conversely, wouldn't it be like, for a first love, this pose is embarrassing or something?
ありえるね。顔がなんかすっごい恥ずかしそうだし。
That's possible. Her face looks super embarrassed.
じゃあ、ノエルは恥ずかしいね。せっかくセクシーに…いや、でも恥ずかしいにしようじゃん。
Then, Noel is embarrassing. Even though she made it sexy... No, let's go with embarrassing.
船長はセクシー！
Captain is sexy!
正解は？もういいのか。正解は…
The correct answer is? Is that it? The correct answer is...
これから私はマリンと一緒に組んでいこうと思います。イエーイ！組んでいこう、イエーイ！
From now on, I plan to team up with Marine. Yay! Let's team up, yay!
じゃあな！じゃあね！え、セクシーだったらもっとこん…こんな感じのさ！足がピーンって…
See ya! See ya! Eh, if it was sexy, it'd be more like... this! With legs straight out...
じゃあ、団長やるよ。
Then Danchou will do it.
うん、じゃあオッケー。じゃあ、せっちゃんも横に…
Yup, okay. Then Set-chan, come over here too...
押さないで、え、ちょっと…あ、あの下の…うーん、ダメなんだよ。
Don't push, eh, wait... Ah, that bottom one... yeah, that's no good.
勘違いしなきゃだめなんだよ。
You have to misunderstand.
あっ…絶望のポーズ！これもう簡単なんじゃないかな？
Ah... Pose of despair! Isn't this pretty easy?
ちょっとマリンマジでその、やばい、え、じゃあ…うん、オッケー。
Wait, Marine, seriously, that's... yikes, eh, then... yup, okay.
じゃあ、視聴者さんにもこれ秘密でやります。これ秘密だからね、視聴者さんにも秘密だから、じゃあ団長秘密なので、やりたいと思います。
Then, we'll do this in secret from the viewers. It's a secret, so it's a secret from the viewers too, so Danchou wants to do it in secret.
オッケー、みんな見て！
Okay, everyone look!
じゃあ団長行く。
Then Danchou is going.
どれどれ？…わかった、わかった、わかった！
Which, which? ...I get it, I get it, I get it!
どれもありえそうなんだけど、いや、これ全身痛すぎて体ガチガチなんやでみたいな方かな？
Any of them seem possible, but no, is it more like "My whole body hurts so much I'm stiff as a board"?
まあそれは筋肉痛つうか？確かに出会ったけど。
Well, is that muscle pain? True, I came across it.
でも、どうなんだろう、この顔見てだって、これ、フィジカルね…眠すぎるから眠れない姿勢をとってる可能性もあるよ。
But I wonder, look at this face, like, physically... she's taking a posture where she can't sleep because she's too sleepy.
これって寝るの？目をかっぴら…眠すぎるから目をかっぴらいて、絶対に眠れない姿勢をとってる。フレア寝る、くっつい…ちょっと離れて、離れて、離れて。
Is she sleeping here? Wide awake... She's wide eyed because she's too sleepy, taking a pose where she definitely can't sleep. Flare sleeping, stick... move away, move away, move away.
じゃあ、早く…眠すぎる。
Then, hurry... too sleepy.
正解は…え、え、フレアが何？
The correct answer is... Eh, eh, what is Flare?
私が全身筋肉痛で、マリンが眠すぎる。
I have full-body muscle pain, and Marine is too sleepy.
おい、ざけんな！ははは！なんでくっついてんじゃ。
Hey, are you kidding me! Hahaha! Why are you sticking to me?
全身筋肉痛で。分かりやすいほうがいいやんね？
With full-body muscle pain. It's better if it's easy to understand, right?
深呼吸をし過ぎ。なんだってめ？
Breathing too much. What'd you say?
答えは全身金…
The answer is full-body mu...
あ、もう言ったのか。いっせーの、かぶり合わっち！
Ah, did you already say it? Ready, set, match!
自意識過剰でした、ということね。自意識過剰こここここにあるじゃん。ポーズ分かんない。
It was over-self-consciousness, that's what it means. Self-consciousness is right here. I don't get the pose.
はい、ということでね。いやあ、どうでした皆さん？みんな正解したかな？
So, yeah. Man, how was it everyone? Did everyone get it right?
どうだったかな？簡単だったな？私簡単だったね、ちょっとこれ簡単すぎた、もっとね、なも…
How was it? Was it easy? I thought it was easy, maybe a bit too easy, even more...
ね、次はね、言うときますと、うん、というわけで
Now, next up, I should mention... yeah, so...
いやこれだけやればね、もうだいぶアイドル力上がったんじゃないの？これ
I mean, if we do this much, our idol power must have gone up quite a bit, right?
セクシーポーズ？
A sexy pose?
セクシーポーズ。これだけやればもうだいぶアイドル力も上がったんじゃないでしょうか。
A sexy pose. If we do this much, wouldn't our idol power have gone up quite a bit?
ということで、そうなったら何が始まると思う？アイドル力上がったわれわれが始めること、それは
So, once that happens, what do you think starts? What we, with our increased idol power, are going to start is...
それは！それは！ホロファオー姉組、アイドルユニットデビュー！
That is! That is! Hololive Older Sisters Unit, Idol Unit Debut!
イヤー！
Yay!
画面の右位置にね、はいじゃあ
Positioned on the right side of the screen, okay, then—
あの、ここね、あの、切り抜いてほしーの。ここここ！
Uh, cut this part out, right here, right here!
絵面地味だろ！はい。
What a boring visual! Yes.
ということでね、ちょっとわれわれ、はい、ちょっとここでね、体力を相当つけたので、
So, you see, since we've built up quite a bit of stamina here,
今のこの一瞬で、もうアップもだいぶ済ましたんでね、ここでね、そろそろ見せようかな、われわれのステージを。
and warmed up quite a bit in this very moment, we should finally show off our stage.
見せちゃうよ。やるか！
We'll show you. Let's do it!
ということで、それでは、行くぜ、ちょっと、行くよ。はい。
So then, let's go, let's go. Okay.
ちょっと、待って待って、先頭がセンター！
Wait, wait, the front is the center!
行こうよ。
Let's go.
えい、来て！
Hey, come!
てててててててて！
Te-te-te-te!
僕はカメ。
I am a turtle.
はあ、こんな海辺で散乱しよっかな。
Ah, I'll scatter around on this beach.
ああ、タマゴームんか？団長に食わされるわ！
Ah, a Tamagomun? You're gonna get eaten by the leader!
うまうまうま！早くタマゴさん乱らしろー！
Delicious! Hurry up and scatter the eggs!
いじめられてるぞ！こらこらこら！すっぺ！うわー！
You're being bullied! Hey hey hey! Sulp! Whoa!
僕はカメ。
I am a turtle.
はあ、こんな海辺で散乱しよっかな。
Ah, I'll scatter around on this beach.
ああ、タマゴームんか？団長に食わされるわ！
Ah, a Tamagomun? You're gonna get eaten by the leader!
うまうまうま！早くタマゴさん乱らしろー！
Delicious! Hurry up and scatter the eggs!
いじめられてるぞ！こらこらこら！すっぺ！うわー！
You're being bullied! Hey hey hey! Sulp! Whoa!
僕はカメ。
I am a turtle.
はあ、こんな海辺で散乱しよっかな。
Ah, I'll scatter around on this beach.
ああ、タマゴームんか？団長に食わされるわ！
Ah, a Tamagomun? You're gonna get eaten by the leader!
うまうまうま！早くタマゴさん乱らしろー！
Delicious! Hurry up and scatter the eggs!
いじめられてるぞ！こらこらこら！すっぺ！うわー！
You're being bullied! Hey hey hey! Sulp! Whoa!
イチゴを食べよう (パフェに ケーキに 大福 みんな 食べたら 幸福)
Let's eat strawberries (parfaits, cakes, daifuku, eat them all and find happiness!)
いろいろ フルーツ (キウイ スウィー ティー ピー ティー くだもの 大好き な もの)
Various fruits (kiwi, sweetie, peach, tea, fruits we love the most!)
冷たい アイスクリーム (冷蔵庫 に 入れ て かたーーーる 最後に ソース を からーーーる)
Cold ice cream (put it in the fridge to harden, lastly drizzle with sauce)
どれ も みんな 好き 。 (優柔不断 な 性格 でも カワイイ 私 は 合格 !)
We love them all. (Even with an indecisive personality, cute me gets a passing grade!)
甘く とろける よう な 味 だけ じゃ 何 か 足りない から ~
It's not just a sweet, melting taste—something is missing, so~
(大好物 を トッピング なければ お店 で ショッピング) ア ・ ラ ・ モード だ ね 。
(If there's no favorite topping, go shopping at the store) It's à la mode.
カリカリ 歯ごたえ ほしい し 甘酸っぱい の も そそられる ~~ わ !
We want a crunchy texture too, and bittersweet things are so tempting~!
デザート だけ は ベツバラ どん欲 に ゆこう !
Dessert has its own stomach, let's go greedily!
トキメキ ドキドキ いろんな 恋 が したい 。
Heart pounding, fluttering—we want all kinds of romance.
近頃 何だか 退屈 な 毎日
Lately, somehow, a boring everyday...
守り に 入る の は まだまだ 早い わ 。
Entering defense mode is still too early.
そういえば つまみ食い も して ない し たくさん 味見 しよ う ~
Come to think of it, I haven't even tasted anything secretly, let's taste a lot~
ア ・ ラ ・ モード だ ね 。
It's à la mode.
カリカリ 歯ごたえ ほしい し 甘酸っぱい の も そそられる ~~ わ !
We want a crunchy texture too, and bittersweet things are so tempting~!
危ない の も 捨て がたい 飛び出し ちゃおう !
Dangerous things are hard to give up on, let's leap out!
トキメキ ドキドキ いろんな 恋 が したい 。
Heart pounding, fluttering—we want all kinds of romance.
カリカリ 歯ごたえ ほしい し 甘酸っぱい の も そそられる ~~ わ !
We want a crunchy texture too, and bittersweet things are so tempting~!
デザート だけ は ベツバラ どん欲 に ゆこう !
Dessert has its own stomach, let's go greedily!
トキメキ ドキドキ いろんな 恋 が したい 。
Heart pounding, fluttering—we want all kinds of romance.
カリカリ 歯ごたえ ほしい し 甘酸っぱい の も そそられる ~~ わ !
We want a crunchy texture too, and bittersweet things are so tempting~!
危ない の も 捨て がたい 飛び出し ちゃおう !
Dangerous things are hard to give up on, let's leap out!
トキメキ ドキドキ いろんな 恋 が したい 。
Heart pounding, fluttering—we want all kinds of romance.
いちごを食べよ
Let's eat strawberries
いろいろフルーツ
Various fruits
つめたいアイスクリーム
Cold ice cream
どれもみんないい。
Everyone is good.
あまくとかれるよ味だけじゃ
Just a sweet, melting taste
なにか足りないから～
is not enough because~
ア・ラ・モードだね。
It's à la mode.
カリカリカリ歯ごたえほしいし
I want a crunchy texture,
あまずっぱいのものそそられる～わ！
sweet and sour is also tempting~!
デザートだけはべつばら どんよくにいこう！
Dessert is a separate stomach, let's go greedily!
ときめきどきどき いろんなことがしたい
Heart-pounding, I want to do all sorts of things!
いちごを食べよ
Let's eat strawberries
いろいろフルーツ
Various fruits
つめたいアイスクリーム
Cold ice cream
え、待って...休憩で...
Eh, wait... for a break...
いや、休む暇ないしこれ
No, we don't have time to rest for this!
いやだって、あのマリンがね、死にそうなんだよ！
I mean, Marine looked like she was about to die!
一旦、一旦ちょっとここで挟ませてあげて下さい。
Please give her a moment to catch her breath here.
ちょっとね、数秒ね、数秒。
Just a few seconds, just a few seconds.
お水いる？お水いる。
Do you want water? I want water.
ねぇ、どうよ？急にビックリしたぁ？
Hey, how is it? Were you surprised all of a sudden?
急にね。
All of a sudden.
スペシャルステージ？そう、しかもこの衣装、この衣装！
A special stage? Yeah, plus this outfit, this outfit!
いやでもマジでさ、フレアさ...
But seriously, Flare...
あ、ちょっと待ってよ！
Ah, wait a minute!
じゃあダメなのかよ？
So is it no good?
いやマリンもかわいい！
No, Marine is cute too!
このもんがらが目にに入らぬかどういうことだよ！
What do you mean by "not seeing these patterns"?
私すごい、本当、本当に行ってる、かわいい！
I'm really, really saying it, cute!
え、でも、なんでも...マリンのね、このバラがかわいいんだよね。
Well, anyway... Marine's rose here is so cute.
私がさっき言ったやつよ！
That's what I said earlier!
ぱくった！
You stole it!
二人が争わないようにするためにな...
To make sure the two of you don't fight...
はし...何？
Hashi... what?
はい、ということでね。
Yes, so...
次の曲いっちゃおう。ちょっとこのね、我々の選曲誰にも予想できまい。
Let's go to the next song. Nobody could have predicted our song choice.
そうだね。船長の配信見てたら予想できる。
That's right. If you watch the Captain's stream, you can guess it.
じゃあ、今日もこの曲好き？
Well, do you like this song today too?
あ、好き？
Ah, you like it?
え、誰？それ、フレア？ノエル？
Eh, who? Is that Flare? Noel?
それでは、お願いします！
Well then, please!
LOVE トロピカーナ！
LOVE Tropicana!
生まれたまんまのジョーネツが火花散らす jungle ハレのちグー！
The raw passion sparks a jungle, clear sky giving way to Guu!
めくるめく腰つきムーチョ 子どもにゃきわどいアミーゴ
An amigo whose dazzling posture is mucho dangerous to children
キスしたら吸い込まれそう 怖いもの見たさ tonight (oh yeah)
When we kiss I feel as if I'll be sucked in; I sure saw some scary stuff tonight
おじけづいちゃダメ (ダメ)
You must not be afraid (no no),
押しちゃ押されて going'
forcibly, forced, you're going!
ドッキリ気分がいいね (いーね)
Surprised? Feels good, doesn't it!
ちゃっかり朝まで dancin' (シュビドゥバ)
Shrewd and dancing till morning
love love love トロピカーナ！
Love love love Tropicana!
ヤシの木陰でつかまえて じらしてとことん とことん
I catch you in the shade of the palm trees; I irritate you to the bitter end
ごめんね あなたはもう虜 逃げられない jungle ハレのちグー！
Sorry, but you are now my captive in this inescapable jungle!
誘惑光線でムーチョ 太陽のせいだわ アミーゴ
There is mucho temptation in the rays of light; it's the sun's fault, amigo!
女の子は天使じゃない 魔物半分 fifty (oh no!)
Girls are not angels; they're fifty percent goblin!
触れりゃ楽しい ok (all right!)
This touching thing is fun!
ちょっと怖いわ moonlight (シャバダバ)
Just a bit scary is the moonlight
骨の髄まで kissin' (おっと) パパヤパパイア danc'n (ドゥビドゥバ)
Completely absorbed in our kissing, dancing the papaya papaya!
love love love トロピカーナ！
Love love love Tropicana!
生まれたまんまのジョーネツが火花散らす jungle ハレのちグー！
The raw passion sparks a jungle, clear sky giving way to Guu!
love トロピカーナ！
Love Tropicana!
飲み込まれてみたいムーチョ 目もくらむ世界へ アミーゴ
I'd mucho like to be gulped down and see that world, amigo!
見たこともない恋だから どきどき隠せぬ tonight (oh yeah)
'Cause this is a love I haven't seen before; an exciting awakening tonight
もじもじしてたらダメ (ダメ) 髪はときましょ moonlight (シャバダバ)
We must not be bashful; let's let down our hair in the moonlight!
甘い夜風にゆれ (ゆれ) ふたり抱かれて danc'n (ドゥビドゥバ)
Sway in this sweet night wind, dancing and before we know it hugging
love love love トロピカーナ！
Love love love Tropicana!
生まれたまんまのジョーネツが火花散らす jungle ハレのちグー！
The raw passion sparks a jungle, clear sky giving way to Guu!
ヤシの木陰でつかまえて じらしてとことん とことん
I catch you in the shade of the palm trees; I irritate you to the bitter end
ごめんね あなたはもう虜 逃げられない jungle ハレのちグー！
Sorry, but you are now my captive in this inescapable jungle!
生まれたまんまのジョーネツが火花散らす jungle ハレのちグー！
The raw passion sparks a jungle, clear sky giving way to Guu!
恋つよ少年少女たち きらりひとみにほし入れて
Strong-loving boys and girls, put a shining star in your eyes!
生まれてまんまのもうじょう熱が
Raw passion
ひばりのちらすヤングるはるれまっく
The jungle scattering sparks of the sunny aftermath!
めくるめく骨付きムチョウ 子供にゃきわどいアミーゴ
Dazzling, bold, mucho, too risky for kids, amigo!
触れ合う楽しいオッケー、ときめくわ、もう来い
Touching is fun, okay, it's exciting, come on!
ある日突然 穏やかな日々 変わっちゃったの
One day, suddenly the gentle days changed.
こっち見ないで ヤダこっち見て ダメどうしよう
Don't look here, no look here! No, what should I do?
沸騰しちゃう 熱すぎます もうムリッムリッ
I'm boiling, I'm too hot! Now, I can't, I just can't!
いつか二人で 手と手繋いで 夕日とか見て
One day, holding hands together, watching the sunset...
想像だけで 夢がメニメニ 昇天しそう
Just imagining it makes my dreams spin and soar.
世界がなんだか きれいなんです
The world somehow looks so beautiful.
予想外の風速ロマンス 規格外のラブ・ヘクトパスカル
An unforeseen wind-speed romance, a non-standard love hectopascal.
渦巻く媚薬の誘惑 どこまでさらわれちゃうの
A swirl of aphrodisiac temptation, where will it carry me away?
やばやばやば 気づいて〜
It's bad, bad, bad! Notice me~
大好き メガ好き 明日はもっと好き
I love you! Mega love you! Tomorrow I'll love you even more!
一斉に舞う花吹雪 これが恋?! かの有名な
All together floating snowstorm, is this love?! That famous...
君だけ 君しか 君こそ 君です
Only you, nobody but you, you're you.
こんなに 全部染まれちゃって 最大級 桃色タイフーン
Colored by you this much, the greatest peach-colored typhoon!
いつも同じ 電車に揺られて 行って帰って
Always on the same train, going and coming back.
だけど時々 アイス食べれば ご機嫌でしタ
Even so, sometimes eating ice cream puts me in a good mood.
切なさなんて 知らなかったの
I didn't know about sadness at all.
雨やどり 不意打ちクランクイン 現れたハート・デスロイヤル
Sheltering from rain, surprise-attack crank-in, heart-destroyer appears.
相合傘 反則ランデブー いったいどうなっちゃうの
Sharing an umbrella, default rendez-vous, what in the world happens?!
ずるいずるい許して〜
Not fair, not fair, forgive me~
警戒体制 近すぎ注意報 一瞬間マジな顔したの
Careful attitude, too close warning, for a moment looking serious...
あれがサイン?! かの王道な 二人が無限に
Is that a sign?! That royal road two of us infinitely...
無限が二人で こんなに全部溶け合っちゃって 歴史的モーメント
Infinity is both of us, dissolving into each other this much, a historical moment!
はぁ〜どこに、はぁ〜どこに、ちょっと、はぁ、ていうことで
Whew... where... so...
はい、じゃあね、ちょっとね、ここね、告知してもよいですか?
Yes, well, we have an announcement here, is that okay?
こっちか、えっとこちに建つんですね。
Over here, um, standing over here.
では、ちょっとね、告知させていただきます、ここで!
Well then, we'd like to make an announcement here!
まあ、まだですね、あの、あれですからね、まだ、まだ曲あるから、まだ曲あるから。
Well, we still have songs left, so wait!
ちょっと告知、その前に
A quick announcement before that...
じゃ、団長の告知からよろしいでしょうか?
Shall we start with Danchou's announcement?
よろしくない! えーーー!
Not okay! Eeeh?!
なになにってんだ! かわいい、かわいいよ。
What are you saying! So cute!
よかった! 団長でまあ、土曜日にも告知したんですけれども。
Yay! Well, Danchou announced it on Saturday too.
団長現在1周年記念ボイス発売中でございます。
Danchou's 1st anniversary voice pack is currently on sale.
なんとね、その時には言い忘れたんです、経由100で
And you know, I forgot to mention back then, through 100...
100マイレで、マイクで一生懸命録ったので、その1時間超え、
Recorded with so much effort for 100 miles on the mic, over 1 hour long!
なんかね、1時間超え、すごい大ボリュームの音源と、あとなんかナイトルーティンみたいな。
Like, over 1 hour of huge volume audio, and also like a night routine.
そうそう、ナイトルーティン撮って、あと団長のね、描き下ろしのアクリルキーホルダーとか丼とか。
Right, taking the night routine, and Danchou's acrylic keychain and rice bowl.
あと父上のポスターカードだったりとか、サイン書くので。
And also Chichiue's postcard, I'll sign them.
もしよければ買ってくださーい! よろしくお願いしまーす。
If you like, please buy it! Thank you very much.
はい、じゃあ、えー、ノエルのやつね、いいよ、すごい。
Yes, well, Noel's is good, really good.
なんだよ! すごい、
What is that! Amazing!
えー、活動一周年記念ボイス、ボイスじゃなくてグッズですね。セットとなってます。
Um, 1st anniversary voice... not voice, goods. It comes as a set.
私の描き下ろしのアクリルキーホルダー、サインを入れて直筆してきました。
My newly drawn acrylic keychain, with my handwritten signature.
や、ほんとにね、今回はね、自分でもたくさん書かせていただきましたので。
Really, this time I drew so many myself.
こちらと、えーと、アクリルスタンド、両面なんで。
This, and um, acrylic stand, it's double-sided.
いや、嬉しいね、これは、どんぶりも。いいネどんぶりも見た目。
Yeah, I'm happy, this rice bowl too. The rice bowl looks nice.
手で進んだよ! 私の後ろで手で進んでた、かわいい!
It advanced by hand! Advancing behind me by hand, so cute!
こうやって、ぴょんぴょん！ひと、ひた、ひた、ちぇ、ちぇ、やったー！
Like this, pyon pyon! Hita hita hita, che che, yay!
金ツバのクッションまでありますからね。
There's even a Kintsuba cushion too!
じゃあ、最後、船長の大事だ、大事だから、耳を傾けながらやろう。
Well then, finally, Captain's important thing, let's listen carefully.
えーっと、はい。というわけで船長の、お知らせはこちらです。
Um, yes. Therefore, Captain's announcement is here.
活動一周年の記念グッズ、えー、本日この配信が終わってから、22時から発売になっております。
1st anniversary goods, starting today after this stream finishes, from 22:00.
記念グッズセットとなっており、どんな内容かというと、船長がこの1年間で描いたイラストをまとめた小冊子です。
It's a booklet compiling illustrations drawn by Captain over this 1 year.
マリーンファーストアニバーサリー2019-2020イラストレーションズ。
Marine First Anniversary 2019-2020 Illustrations.
えー、宝鐘海賊団 海賊旗ピンバッチ、これ嬉しいでしょ?
Houshou Pirates Jolly Roger pin badge, aren't you happy with this?
と、なんとここからですね、AセットとBセットとあるんですけど、ちょっと出します。
And, amazingly from here, there's set A and set B, let me show you.
Tシャツのデザインが違うんです。あとで見せ散らかす。
The T-shirt designs are different. I'll show them around later.
はい、で、イングリッシュバージョン。ファーストアニバーサリーオブデビュードイリュージョン、コモナ、コモナラ、コモナリティ、グーヅ。
Yes, and, English version. First anniversary of debut commemorative goods.
Aセット、Aセットイズ、あ、ちが、待って、えっと、え、ブックレット、マイイラストレーションズブックレット。
Set A, Set A is, ah no, wait, um, booklet, my illustrations booklet.
アンド、え、パイレーツ、ホウショウ、ピンバッチ、アンド、え、Tシャツ、デザイン、イズ、Aイズ...
And, pirates Houshou pin badge, and, T-shirt design is A...
B Tシャツ is...
B T-shirt is...
あかさあい先生、えーデザインズTシャツイズ、えーこれは
Designed by Akasa Ai-sensei, um, the design T-shirt, um, this is
えー、ビューティフルマリンデザインズ、
um, a Beautiful Marine design,
といったような内容になっております。
is what it contains.
あ、そうだ！あともう一個付いてるものがあって、えっとね、活動い…あ、ステッカーがついてます。
Oh, that's right! There's one more thing included—um, a activity... ah, a sticker is included.
ステッカーがね、ちょっとね、あのね、いろんな絵柄があって、あのあかさあい先生が今まで描いて下さったイラストを、え、シールにしたり、
The stickers, you know, have various designs that Akasa Ai-sensei has drawn so far turned into seals,
センチョウの描いた絵がシールになってたり、なんかいろんなシールなん、なんでちょっといろいろ多くてまだ、まとめなくて画像が出せないんですけど、いろんなシールです。
or the Captain's drawings turned into seals, there are various seals so... since there are so many and I haven't put them together to show images yet, there are all sorts of seals.
あっちこっちにペタペタ貼って宝鍾マリンで遊んでんな！ぬか！
Stick them everywhere and have fun with Houshou Marine! What the heck!
そうしてもう一個大事なお知らせがあります。
And there is another important announcement.
こちら、あ、これ逆だわ。かわいい。
Here—ah, this is backwards. Cute.
こちらどどーん！こちらもなんと！センチョウのオリジナル楽曲！
Here, ta-da! This is also, unbelievably, the Captain's original song!
これがですね、なんと、えーついに配信されることになりました。えーとね、ちょっと待ってね、今紙見てるから…えーっと
This, unbelievably, um, is finally going to be released. Um, wait, let me check my notes... um...
そして、明日8月12日の、え、0時から「Ahoy!! 我ら宝鐘海賊団☆」がiTunes、Apple Music、Spotifyの各サービスでリリースされます。
And tomorrow, August 12th, at 0:00, "Ahoy!! We Are the Houshou Pirate Crew☆" will be released on iTunes, Apple Music, Spotify, and other services.
それに伴って宝鍾マリン誕生日記念ボイズ2020の、あの今まで出てたやつですね、誕生日記念ボイスについていたオリジナル楽曲特典付きセットは、本日23時までの販売になります。
Along with that, the set with the original song bonus included in Houshou Marine's Birthday Commemorative Voice 2020 (the ones released previously) will be on sale until 23:00 today.
わかります？あの、すでに持ってる方は、は、変わらず聞けます。で、あの配信サイトの方でこのジャケット付きで配信されるという感じですね。
You understand? Those who already have it can still listen to it. And it will be distributed with this jacket on the streaming sites.
あの、誕生日グッズの方についてた歌は、なくなるということです。
The song that came with the birthday merchandise will no longer be available separately.
わかっていただけました？ということで
Do you understand? With that said,
はい、詳しくはTwitterで。
yes, details are on Twitter.
では最後の曲いきますか。
Now, shall we go to the last song?
いきましょう。サックリ、サックリ行こう、サックリ。
Let's go. Quickly, let's go quickly, quickly.
それでは…うん。サックリ。
Well then... yeah. Quickly.
ミュージック！スタート！
Music! Start!
重ねた手はギュッと離さずに
Without letting go of our intertwined hands,
行くよ 夢見る空へ
let's go toward the sky of our dreams!
長い星に見上げたとても小さな空
The tiny sky I looked up at for a long time,
ここで出逢えたのは数え切れない奇跡
finding you here is an uncountable miracle.
繰り出した一歩がきらめきを繋いで 星のような笑顔を導いた
The step we took out connected the sparkle and guided a starry smile.
Day by Day みんなの声が力になる
Day by day, everyone's voice becomes my strength.
Step by Step ここでそれぞれ目指すもの
Step by step, what each of us aims for here,
それぞれ描くもの それぞれ願う夢
what each depicts, each dream we wish for...
重ねた手はギュッと離さずに
Without letting go of our intertwined hands,
1人1人違ういのちが描き出すトキメキ
the excitement painted by each and every different life
振り向くことなくまっすぐに 行くよ 夢見る空へ
moving straight ahead without looking back, let's go to the sky of our dreams!
1人1人違ういのちが描き出すトキメキ
The excitement painted by each and every different life
振り向くことなくまっすぐに 行くよ 夢見る空へ
moving straight ahead without looking back, let's go to the sky of our dreams!
笑い合ったことや付きそうにない笑い
Things we laughed about together, endless laughter,
想い出いっぱいなのにあっというまの日々
though filled with memories, the days passed in the blink of an eye.
上書きじゃなくて名前つけて保存 どっちも全部大事で生き切れる
Not overwriting, but naming and saving—both are entirely precious and let us live fully.
Ah, For All みんなの為が力になる
Oh, for all, everyone's sake becomes my strength.
Oh, For All みんなの為が力になる
All For All 今日を賑やかすぎるくらい笑顔が止まらない
All for all, today is so lively that smiles won't stop,
想いは膨らんでいく
and feelings keep expanding.
重ねた今ギュッと噛み締めたい
I want to cherish this stacked-up present tightly.
1人1人違う声で歌えば 声は広がる
If each of us sings in our own unique voice, the voice spreads out.
風を感じたらまっすぐに 行くよ 夢見る空へ
Feeling the wind, let's go straight ahead to the sky of our dreams!
憧れて伸ばした つかみ取った その光が
The light I reached out for and grasped,
いつしか また誰かのあこがれに変わる
someday will turn into someone else's admiration.
重ねた手は ギュッと 離さずに
With our joined hands held tight, never letting go,
行くよ！
Let's go!
夢見る空へ
To the sky of our dreams!
聞きたいんだろ？ もっと叫べ！
You want to hear it? Scream more!
今日の主役はマリン！
Today's star is Marine!
重ねた手は ギュッと 離さずに
With our joined hands held tight, never letting go,
ひとり ひとり 違う 色で
Each in our own different colors,
描き出す ドキドキ
Painting our fluttering hearts.
出会った 全てに ありがとう
Thank you for all our encounters.
奇跡だって 更新し続けると ずっと側にいるよ
If we keep updating our miracles,
I'll always be by your side.
行くよ！
Let's go!
もっと夢見る空へ
To the ever-dreaming sky!
みんな大好き！
We love you all!